<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>untagged on Art projects</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/tags/untagged/</link><description>Recent content in untagged on Art projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:01:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://digitalitility.com/tags/untagged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Snorre</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/05/snorre/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:01:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/05/snorre/</guid><description>Snorre features intersectangles. On two layers rectangles intersect with each other and give birth to new colorful areas.
Format: 4000x4000px, .png image.
Every earned Tezo, primary and secondary, earned from this project towards the NGO Save the Children https://thegivingblock.com/donate/save-the-children/. The donation is done after about 30 days.
Created with p5.js, 100% generative, no pngs
The source code is published here: https://github.com/sektionschef/Snorre
Published on fxhash: https://www.fxhash.xyz/generative/13907</description></item><item><title>Raumstreicher</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/03/raumstreicher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 17:01:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/03/raumstreicher/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;I paint energy, not the soul.&amp;rdquo; Ukranian artist Kazimir Malevich, 1924
100% of primary and secondary sales are donated to Save the children (https://thegivingblock.com/donate/save-the-children/) one week after publication, supporting victims of the war against Ukraine.
Raumstreicher divides space in boxes, randomly.
Shortcuts &amp;rsquo;s&amp;rsquo; | export png image &amp;lsquo;c&amp;rsquo; | center the artwork &amp;lsquo;r&amp;rsquo; | reset the perspective scrolling | zoom in and zoom out left-clicking + dragging | rotate the camera right-clicking + dragging | pan the camera position 100% generative, created with p5.</description></item><item><title>Landstreicher</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/02/landstreicher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 17:01:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/02/landstreicher/</guid><description>A couple of strokes wandering through the landscapes.
The space is randomly cut in segments on both axis. Some of the resulting rectangles are randomly selected to be paired. A second layer with similar ingredients is placed on top.
stroke size is randomly chosen and gets distorted along the way spacing between the hatches is relative to the stroke size speed of the strokes is randomly chosen for each line stroke color is randomly distorted the background noise is randomly generated 12 palettes with 2 colors 100% generative, no pngs.</description></item><item><title>Alberto Tomba</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/02/alberto-tomba/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 17:01:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/02/alberto-tomba/</guid><description> The digital painting combines paint with physics, as generative piece of art. It differs in variations of gravity and explosion force and is listed on fxhash: https://www.fxhash.xyz/generative/8871
The code repo is here: https://github.com/sektionschef/wash</description></item><item><title>Busta Verde</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/02/busta-verde/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 17:01:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/02/busta-verde/</guid><description> The digital painting is the little sister of the generative CO² canvas. It differs in variations of gravity, color and position of the elements and was sold on fxhash: https://www.fxhash.xyz/generative/8291
The code repo is here: https://github.com/sektionschef/hashy_bashy</description></item><item><title>CO² emissions in digital painting</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/01/co-emissions-in-digital-painting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 17:01:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2022/01/co-emissions-in-digital-painting/</guid><description> The digital painting visualizes the increasing CO² concentration in the earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere between 2012 and 2021. It&amp;rsquo;s a generative piece of art which never looks the same.
The artwork itself is here: https://sektionschef.github.io/generative_co2/ More information here -&amp;gt; https://medium.com/@sektionschef/co%C2%B2-emissions-in-digital-painting-3e979c2e6a04 The code repo is here: https://github.com/sektionschef/generative_co2 the clean nft OBJKT is here: https://hicetnunc.art/objkt/624714</description></item><item><title>Donation</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/donation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/donation/</guid><description>I will donate every earned tezos from my art projects to the NGO Save the children via The Giving Block. I will keep a kind of safety level of 111 ꜩ in my wallet. Everything above it will be donated.
The following transactions have already been made:
102 ꜩ (275 €) , Mar 13 2022 - transaction details 24 ꜩ (72 €), Mar 20 2022 - transaction details 135 ꜩ (216 €), Jun 10 2022 - transaction details 349 ꜩ (590 €), Jul 18 2022 - transaction details</description></item><item><title>COVID-19 on abstract painting</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2020/09/covid-19-on-abstract-painting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2020/09/covid-19-on-abstract-painting/</guid><description>Read the whole story here: https://medium.com/@sektionschef/abstract-painting-visualizes-regional-covid-19-infections-in-real-time-b43b6c2a9e70</description></item><item><title>Paintings</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2015/01/paintings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2015/01/paintings/</guid><description> Nagano - Acrylic on canvas, 160x100cm Wühlmaus Skeleton Staro Magazino Dochboden Schuachschochtl 1 Schuachschochtl 2 Schuachschochtl 3</description></item><item><title>Hello world, hello futuregarden</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/11/hello-world-hello-futuregarden/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/11/hello-world-hello-futuregarden/</guid><description>What an honor: my projection painting prototype was publicly featured in futuregarden for 2 weeks. The original canvas was repainted with 5 different colors.
At the entrance of the futuregarden a beamer, a laptop running my processing script (here at github), an arduino uno and a hall sensor were hooked up. The beamer pointing at the canvas projected five additional colors to create five new colors.
Each time the door of the futuregarden was opened and somebody entered or left.</description></item><item><title>Data Painting - The Past in Realtime</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/09/data-painting-the-past-in-realtime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/09/data-painting-the-past-in-realtime/</guid><description>After the infamous projection prototype, my first work is finished: the past in realtime. It displays our team&amp;rsquo;s diverging efforts for each minute of the day on a painted canvas. Based on the data of 51.000 time entries of ambuzzador&amp;rsquo;s past, the painting explains the distribution of our working time for six categories: project management, meetings, conceptual design, consulting, editorial services and content creation. For each minute, six color tones are projected on variably sized, painted areas.</description></item><item><title>Projection Painting Prototype</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/07/projection-painting-prototype/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/07/projection-painting-prototype/</guid><description>Executive Summary The structure of the canvas, mixing colors right on the canvas, layer after layer and letting the coincidence help is what makes traditional painting so powerful. However, as a nerdophile person I often miss the undo button and the color wheel of the digital world.
Luckily, I came across the processing movement turning code into art and vice versa. The perfect base to combine vivid richness of painted structure with the interactive and dynamic power of code.</description></item><item><title>Like Converter</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/04/like-converter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/04/like-converter/</guid><description>The Like Converter transforms likes earned for a Facebook posting into delicious candy. It is a reward system for social media managers and a source of motivation for your desk.
The thing itself is built (like the [Twetterhaeuschen] (https://digitalitility.com/posts/2013/11/twetterh%C3%A4uschen/ )) on a raspberry pi, an arduino uno using node.js and firmata. The source code is on github: https://github.com/sektionschef/like_converter</description></item><item><title>Die Dübitale Revolution</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/03/die-d%C3%BCbitale-revolution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2014/03/die-d%C3%BCbitale-revolution/</guid><description>Bayrische Großvisionäre haben das Tor zu einer neuen Dimension aufgestoßen. Die &amp;ldquo;Dübitalanzeige&amp;rdquo; besteht aus einem Holzbrett, in das durch präzise Bohrungen einzelne Dübel von Hand variabel angeordnet werden können. Je nach Dübelsetzung kann so, eine gewisse geistige Flexibilität vorausgesetzt, eine kurze Botschaft encodiert werden, ohne ein einziges Watt zu verbrauchen.
Die &amp;ldquo;Dübitalanzeige&amp;rdquo; ist der erste große Schritt Richtung dübitaler Ära. Ob das Pixel tatsächlich dem Düxel Platz machen werden muss, wird sich erst in den nächsten Jahren herauskristallisieren.</description></item><item><title>Twetterhäuschen</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2013/11/twetterh%C3%A4uschen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2013/11/twetterh%C3%A4uschen/</guid><description>The Twetterhäuschen is the world&amp;rsquo;s first Wetterhäuschen for visualizing the sentiment of a specific topic on twitter. It was built on a raspberry pi, a servo controlled by an arduino uno, using node.js in combination with socket.io. You can find the code on github to build your own: https://github.com/sektionschef/twetterhaeuschen
Implementation The Twetterhäuschen has its web form (index.html) to fill a brand or topic of interest The keyword is passed on to the server (app.</description></item><item><title>Animation in the command line - ./animation.sh</title><link>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2012/01/animation-in-the-command-line-./animation.sh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 12:27:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://digitalitility.com/posts/2012/01/animation-in-the-command-line-./animation.sh/</guid><description>Why After finding out how much one can do with ffmpeg&amp;hellip; I thought it would be the perfect tool for creating my abstract stop-motion animation I dreamed of for years. What I wanted to realize was simple: combining scenes of a series of high resolution photographs, including images of paintings and digitally edited material with various lengths, framerates exactly timed to a soundtrack.
Ffmpeg is a powerful tool to convert audio and video files (among other things).</description></item></channel></rss>